Will the master come on a tour somewhere?
I will. I was going to go on all of them.
What?
All of them?
The whole tour?
The whole thing.
Oh, I'm so glad.
There's the Kawasaki, for example.
Carutz.
Karutz.
Karutz, Kawasaki.
What do they do, do they come back one by one and split up?
No, depending on the region, we stay overnight in some places.
But this time we usually just go home.
They come back, yes.
Let's hear more about that next time.
Yes, by all means.
Okay, a block of gold.
Okay, by all means.
But first, let's do our best to get something going.
Can I make a quick motion? Yes, yes.
Yes, yes.
Yeah. - Yeah.
Well, that's about it.
Okay.
Yo, yo, yo, yo.
Yo yo, rap
Rap starting with the master
Let's go!
No, it's not “let's go.
No, I don't get it at all, why rap let's go! No, it's not a let's go! No, it's not a let's go!
Why rap?
And...
What's up?
What's wrong?
Your nose?
You see the nose? It's here. You have it, don't you? This.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Something like that.
Buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh-buh.
Yeah.
It rhymes, right?
Rhyme, so for example
I'm still trying to get it right.
Oh, wow!
I'm a high school girl
Still, still, still
Ganbandani, ha, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani, ganbandani today
Fire
No, no, no, no, this ain't rap any more, at least
Sentence
I was thinking, “Ganbandani,” you know...
Like, let's work a little harder.
I'm sure it is.
Welcome!
It's a coffee shop.
With pleasure.
Since when did this become a pub?
- Good! - With pleasure!
- Mr. Partly! Mr. Partly! Please, have a canteen! - Thank you!
- Thank you very much! - What would you like to order?
You're early. I haven't seen the menu yet.
- It's developing fast. It's developing fast. - It's early.
- Well, well, well. So, you know, right now, Evijon is on tour, all over the country. How many shows are you doing? Oh, that.
All of them.
It was amazing when I saw it today, wasn't it?
A lot of them.
I'll be fine.
Don't worry.
But I get to go to Sapporo in Hokkaido this time.
For the first time?
I went to Tomakomai last time.
I've been to Hokkaido, but this time I'm going to Sapporo.
Sapporo is a nice, bustling city. Sapporo is a nice, bustling city.
I'm looking forward to it!
I can't wait to go.
I was thinking that you've been around for so long.
I've been all over Japan for such a long time.
Hokkaido, for example.
Hokkaido now.
It's totally possible to make a day trip there.
It's a lot faster by plane now.
Do they sometimes stop?
Yes, they do.
If it's far away...
Sometimes they stop.
Or the next day.
Like Ren-chan, you know... she goes there and goes back the same day.
Well, I mean, I guess we all do a lot of gigs during the daytime, but what do we do at night?
I imagine it's like a junior high school trip... everyone's doing their own thing... going to concerts... having fun.
So come on over and have fun... tax on the names of people you like, like, like... there's school... there's school... there's school...
The teacher was pretending to be asleep and snoring on purpose.
I'm sure he didn't do that.
Back then... school trips...
What was it like?
Do you fall asleep because you're tired?
That's right.
Most of us were already cooing.
But I was usually with Balikata.
And I get together with Subie.
I get together with Kokon and Hanamichi.
My sister members are relatively close to each other.
The older sister members are already asleep.
They do their own thing.
So the sister members often get together
We play games and talk.
You said bad things about the older sisters, didn't you?
No, we didn't.
He really pisses me off.
I didn't. I didn't say that.
I didn't.
That's fun, isn't it?
No, it's not fun.
You're too social, aren't you? That's what I'm thinking.
Is it?
Bad-mouthing your boss.
It's like talking shit about your boss.
Like a boss.
You know what I mean.
Just like a boss.
Talking bad about other people is a lot of fun.
I don't know what it is, but...
It's like a drinking party.
I see. Well, I think...
I think that going to concerts in the countryside is... well... when I was a teenager...
When I was a teenager, I hardly ever went out of the prefecture for a family vacation.
I might go out of the prefecture for a family trip or something, but I think it's a great thing.
It's true.
I didn't go on family vacations until I was in junior high school.
I only went to my grandma's house.
Now that I'm in Ebichu, I'm so happy to be able to go so many places.
I'm so happy!
I've never been to Hokkaido either.
I was 23 or 24 the first time I flew.
I'd never been on a plane before.
Airplanes are scary, aren't they?
It's scary at first.
It's good to experience things while you're young.
In the future, there will be things you can only think of then.
That's right.
Only when you're young.
That kind of sensitivity.
I'm a bit dried up in terms of sensitivity.
Is that so?
I don't like it when you answer seriously.
You're a blabbermouth.
What? Blur. What? It's a blur.
Well, okay, it's like half a blur.
It's hard to tell.
I've been thinking about it all week.
I've been thinking about what I said, and I'm thinking, “Well, this is half-true.
I don't know what I'm going to do.
But, you know, when you're doing this kind of work, it's really important.
You know, another one of those work-related things that happen all over the country.
Even though it's work-related.
It makes you happy, doesn't it?
It makes me happy.
That uplifting feeling.
For example, in Sapporo, when you arrive at Chitose Airport, you're happy, aren't you?
For example, in Sapporo...
Arriving at Chitose Airport...
Then you can take a train or an express bus or something like that.
By train or highway bus...
I saw the city of Sapporo in a flash.
Like, “Oh!
Oh, that whisky man's sign
The famous one.
That's it!
That's Sapporo!
Seeing that kind of thing
You really feel it.
Yes.
People on the street say.
Don't say you're from Yokohama, don't say you're from Yokohama, don't say you're from Yokohama, don't say you're from Yokohama
Don't be cheap, and definitely don't go with them.
I'd love to go with you... but I'm not sure I'd like to go with you...
I don't feel like I'm talking in a dialect when I talk with the locals.
When you talk with locals in Hokkaido, you don't really feel like you're talking to them in their dialect.
They are like, “Oh, Fukuoka, here we are!
That's right, that's right, that's right.
We are really grown-ups without a dialect, aren't we?
I wish we had a little bit of standard Japanese.
So they envy us for that too.
But that's why they call it standard Japanese. But that's why, you see, the so-called standard language
Like what we speak.
On TV, for example, on NHK news, it's normal.
So people over there watch it too, right?
That's right.
That's not what I mean.
That's not what I meant.
It's just something you can only hear there.
I get it.
It's like a dialect.
I heard Yokohama has it too.
They say something about it, don't they?
It's called “jan” in Yokohama
I don't know what “jan” means.
People say it all the time.
Maybe it's a word around here.
Something like “dabe”.
Dabe... Dabe, too.
You also say “dabe” and “jan” and “dame” and “jan”...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Let's see, shall we? Let's start right away...
It's a living thing?
I was so surprised... because I was expecting it to be loud.
I was surprised that it wasn't that big of a deal.
I think it's not only loud voices that surprise people.
That's why I've been given this subject.
Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo, on the heat.
Thank you very much.
Good evening, everyone.
This is Tokyo Bunkyo Ward, Tokyo, Japan.
This is a contribution to the corner of creature creation.
So this time, I'm going to talk about Spanish.
Spanish, paella.
I don't understand.
Can I?
Calamar.
It's Spanish for “calamaal,” “calamaal,” “calamaal,” yes, it's Spanish. In Spanish, there is a creature called calamar, which is a Spanish word.
There's a creature called “calamar” in Spanish.
So when the Spanish hear it, they say the creature's name so loudly!
Calamar
That's why
Calamar.
I can't imagine what it is at all
Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you, Calamar, I have no idea.
But I can tell you one thing.
It's in Spanish.
But there's a clue hidden in there.
What?
I think there's a clue hidden in there, and it's in Spanish.
I'm gonna write my name down first.
Calamar.
It's like that one, isn't it?
It's like the name of a drug.
Boraginol.
Only the last one.
Or something that makes you feel better right away.
Yes, that's true.
Sverrez, for example. It's so tangled.
It's so tangled, you know?
Oh!
Yes, yes, yes.
I got it.
Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
I knew it. Mr. Energy Saving Suit is really kicking ass these days. Really.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I knew I missed a sleeveless suit.
I missed it when I saw it this week.
Really?
I thought it was an energy-saving suit. I thought it was an energy-saving suit.
But it was over too soon.
I mean, it was over.
I mean, that was probably connected to the current eco-consciousness and SDGs.
It led to the SDGs.
It was like a precursor to the SDGs.
Don't think that resources are infinite.
At the time when the movement like “Don't think that resources are infinite forever!
So the general public wasn't doing that at all.
But people like the members of the Diet
People like that were willing to do that.
They wore short-sleeved suits here.
They were wearing short-sleeved suits, right?
I miss those days.
I'm going to start from here.
Yes, that's right.
Okay, here we go.
Let's start with energy-saving suits.
Let's start with the energy-saving suit.
This way
Bam!
Oh!
It's all tangled up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't know what that means, but...
what do you mean?
I don't understand.
My tongue...
I got tangled up in it.
Like a spit.
Oh...
What is this?
What's going on?
It's exactly what it looks like.
What kind of creature is it?
A llama?
Karamma. Karamma
Llama
Earl.
I'm pretty sure there was a llama or something.
Are you a person who does something?
I'll do it, I'll do it, I'll do it.
Stinky breath.
Is that what he was like?
That's right.
Llama.
Does this mean it's tangled?
Yes, it's tangled.
This one is tangled.
That's what I mean.
Yes, yes, yes.
Well, I did my best.
I'm not sure I can do it either.
Kalamar
I don't get it.
Hmm?
Wait a minute.
Um, I don't know.
Calamar's Kara.
Empty-headed.
Kara the sword.
So, um, Kara, is she the empty-headed one?
Hey, empty, hole, empty head? This one.
After you're the one with the, you know, empty head.
Don't shift towards me, you camera.
Don't switch, you camera.
This is malicious.
Malicious, me? I'm empty-headed? Like...
If that's the case, maybe it's like this, or maybe it's a talker, or maybe it's a big talker.
I'm spinning.
I'm spinning with you.
Oh, it's the “stuck in the air” type.
That's amazing. That's amazing.
He's so empty.
I'd be scared to death if he came here.
But it's kind of cute.
Well, well, well. I think he'll be cute after he's lived with us for a year or so.
He's kind of scary at the moment.
I don't know what he's gonna do... because he's so empty.
But it can run and walk.
Yes, on two legs.
Four legs.
That's amazing.
So, Kalamazoo is...
It's Spanish for...
It means “squid.
Icy.
Squid is also Spanish.
I don't think it means “calamar”.
It's a little bit like “kalamal”.
It's like the Japanese word for squid.
I love squid, by the way.
So this time, I'd like to express my respect for squid.
I usually do it in a short time.
But this took about 30 minutes.
I made those dots all the time.
First of all, the dots are very realistic.
It's like this.
I don't know how you do it.
Well, well, well... let's just say...
Well, well, well, there's not much difference.
Well, it's true that they're all painted over.
I'd say... they're probably almost the same.
They were drawn by the same person.
It's a bit like a borderline here.
Well, well, well...
We'll continue with the creation of living creatures.
If you have any suggestions, please send them to me.
I'd like you to close this block with the same one as before. So, please give me the example of this block closing.
Not yet this week.
Yes, it is.
That's for sure.
Well, I'll leave you to it.
Let's go.
I'm going to let you all join me in a ganbari fire.
Yes!
Thank you very much.
Fire!
Thank you.